[theme music playing]
[tense music playing]
[screaming]
[shattering sound]
[Julio] Tell me the truth, Ivy.
Who shot Arnaldo?!
It was a man!
You were the one who shot my grandson!
-[Ivy gasps]
-You!
[Diego] Auntie, we had no choice.
Lily would've been exposed--
When Arnaldo wakes up, Lily's done for!
If she doesn't call, I'm going
with you to the Ardientes.
[Ivy] I'm with the Ardientes.
Don't worry. I'm safe.
Don't do anything that
might get you killed.
Do you understand me?
[Camia] Arnaldo is like
a ticking time bomb.
We must speed up our plans.
Miss Cora is our only witness
against Emilia.
I'll sneak into her house in Sitio Nueve
and look for evidence against Emilia.
[Raul] I'm so close
to bringing Julio down.
So I won't give you back your title.
[Damian] I am the real Jaguar!
Tell him to give me back
-my men, my money, my weapons.
-[gunshot]
[crowd screaming]
[Julio] Either you tell me the truth
or you watch me unleash hell.
[Ivy] If you kill me,
it'll be like you killed
your only real grandson!
[Julio] You may have passed all the tests
but that doesn't mean you're off the hook.
[man] I saw two men fleeing
the crime scene.
I'll never forget their faces.
[Jose] It's Diego Torillo and
your former employee, Madrigal.
-Lily.
-Mom.
[Camia] Sweetheart.
Lily, you risked your life again.
That's why I can't wait
for all this to be over.
Wait, you have a bruise.
-Are you really all right?
-Mom, it's nothing.
It's just a bruise.
What's important is I was able
to fool the Ardientes.
I know it's hard, Mom.
But we have to endure for a bit more.
We're so close to ending
the Ardientes' tyranny.
Lily…
we need to send Emilia to
prison as soon as possible.
Yes, Mom.
But I'm still worried about you.
You've spent most of your life
trying to bring the Ardientes to justice.
I'm afraid that because
of what you're doing,
the wounds in your heart might never heal.
You never know what could happen.
You might be gone tomorrow.
And you didn't even
give yourself a chance to fall in love.
Lily…
I don't want your heart
to be filled with anger.
I don't want it to take away
your ability to love.
Lily, you know we love you, right?
We all do. Jepoy, Anna…
Mom, I know.
I know that. I know that you love me.
I'm doing all this
because of my love for you.
For you, Anna, Jepoy,
Miss Loring, Mr. Pandoy,
and all the people of this town.
I'm doing all this for you guys.
But I love Jepoy as a friend.
He does everything for me.
He even risks his life for me.
I just hope someday, he'll meet a woman…
who will truly love him.
What about Diego?
Diego is part of my life.
He does everything for me too.
He's my ally.
He accepts everything about me.
He makes so many sacrifices.
He even understood
why I had to marry Arnaldo,
even though the thought
itself disgusted me.
But he's always there for me.
Mom, I have a feeling Diego
and I have a future together.
That's why I'm working hard on my plans,
so we can all be happy.
[sentimental music playing]
I'm not sure who between them
fired the gun.
But I'm sure of one thing.
Those two were there that night.
Colonel.
This is a lot of money, Congressman.
That's your reward.
I just need you to do one thing.
Don't tell anyone…
about the information you
just told me. Is that clear?
It's a promise, Congressman.
Thank you very much, Congressman.
-All right. You may leave.
-Go on.
Thank you.
What should we do about these two?
Give me the best hitmen
you can find, Colonel.
Tell them that I have
a shoot-to-kill order…
against Madrigal…
and that bastard, Diego Torillo.
I want them dead!
I want them dead.
As in yesterday!
[tense music playing]
I'm so lucky. The congressman is the best.
[bodyguard] Keep it down.
[ominous music playing]
I want to see Arnaldo.
Nice of you to visit him
despite what happened.
I've moved on, Congressman.
So let's forget about it.
What's important is…
I was able to prove my innocence.
Good.
Please take good care of him.
That's what I always do.
[suspenseful music playing]
[Anna] Miss Cora is our only
witness against Emilia.
[Diego] I'll sneak into her
house in Sitio Nueve
and look for evidence against Emilia.
[Jepoy] Sitio Nueve?
Diego, the residents
there are pro-Ardiente.
If they see you, they'll mob you.
Diego.
Anna, what are you doing here?
I told you I'd help, remember?
I know Cora's address too, so I came here.
We'll be in grave danger
if anyone sees you here.
-Now go. Go home.
-No, Diego.
I'm here now! It's too late for that.
So just let me help you. Hurry.
Who told you to come here?
Hurry.
There.
-You got it?
-Let's move.
[door creaking]
Anna, be on the lookout.
Let me know if you see anyone approaching.
-Okay.
-Hold these.
-All right.
-Lock the door.
I'll be quick.
[Ivy] Will you step out, please?
I want to be alone with him.
I'm sorry, ma'am,
but we can't leave the mayor.
Why not? On whose orders?
The congressman's.
[upbeat music playing]
You know my secret, Arnaldo,
so I can't let you wake up yet.
I'm not done with your family.
I need to earn the congressman's trust
so I can destroy Emilia.
[upbeat music playing]
[suspenseful music playing]
Rudy, Kenneth, come out here!
Hurry! Call the cops! I saw some thieves.
[woman] Hurry!
-Guys--
-What is it?
-Victor… come out.
-What's wrong?
-I saw some thieves at Cora's place.
-Thieves?
All right. Let's go.
[suspenseful music playing]
WOMEN'S UNION
Dexter! Hurry up!
Diego, the neighbors are
on their way here!
They're coming for us! Hurry it up there!
Hurry!
They're almost here!
Keep a close eye on that woman.
Doesn't the congressman
have other suspects in mind?
Why is he still suspicious about Aguas?
[Jose] The congressman
doesn't trust her at all.
So quit yapping, just do your job.
Yes, sir.
[Julio] Remember those two faces.
One million for Madrigal's body.
And another million for Diego's corpse.
[Diego] Come on. Let's move.
Are you sure about what you saw?
Yeah. I saw a guy with a flashlight.
[Diego whispers]
No. We can't get out here.
Over here. Let's go up. Come on.
Open the door! Move!
-Hurry up!
-Turn the lights on!
[Anna, hushed] Can we fit in there?
[hushed] No, it's too cramped.
They're probably out back.
Come on! Let's go.
[hushed] It's locked.
[Anna, hushed] There's a door there.
[Bata] Hey! There's no one here!
[Diego, hushed] Over here.
I heard something upstairs.
-They're upstairs!
-[whispers] Hurry!
[Bata] They're upstairs! Move!
-They're upstairs.
-Move, move, move!
-Move it! They might get away!
-Hurry.
-What?
-They're not here.
-Check over there.
-All right. Careful.
[door closing]
[Bata] Check that out.
[Bata] Did you find them?
Let's go.
-What?
-Let's go.
Diego, what do we do?
Anna, we're going to jump.
-What?
-Hold this. I'll catch you.
-Be careful. Please.
-Come on.
Anna… Anna, jump.
-Well?
-Check over there.
-It's empty.
-They're not here. It's clear.
Anna, hurry up. They might catch us. Jump!
[grunts] Come on.
I saw something. Outside.
[woman] Hey! They're outside!
-Outside?
-Let's go!
[Bata] They're outside!
[woman] Hurry up! We have to catch them!
-Hurry! They're outside!
-[man] Move it!
-Hurry up!
-Hurry up! Come on!
[Bata] There! Run after them! Hurry!
-Get them!
[woman] Hurry! We have to catch them!
My goodness! They got away.
What did they steal?
Cora!
Cora, some thieves broke into your house!
-What?
-They broke in.
They got away.
Aunt Camia, look at this.
We got that from Miss Cora's house.
Diego, Anna, these are
really important documents.
[Diego] We have to inform Ivy.
[phone ringing]
-Hello?
-[Diego] Ivy.
We have to meet.
We have some good news.
-All right.
-Take care.
Ivy's on her way.
She has to see these.
[phone ringing]
-Emilia?
-Hello, Jaguar?
I've been trying to call you.
Why? What's the problem?
You told me you'd do everything
for me, remember?
Now is the time to prove that.
My son, Arnaldo, was shot…
…and I suspect that Ivy Aguas
had something to do with it.
Make her pay for what she did to my son.
I'm sorry, Emilia, but I
can't help you this time.
Why? What's wrong?
We're on red alert.
There's an impostor pretending to be me.
Be careful.
[stammers] Hello?
-[Natalie] Hi, boys.
-Ma'am.
Hello.
Are you new here?
You look so familiar.
What's your name again?
Madrigal, ma'am.
Have we met before?
Uh…
Actually, I was assigned
to guard you before.
I used to be Arnaldo's bodyguard.
Oh, I see.
So, why are you
on the other side of the fence?
I've turned my back on the Ardientes.
They owe me a great deal.
I know how that feels.
To be betrayed by the people you trust.
I get it.
-[Raul] Natalie.
-Boss.
Bye.
Jepoy.
I'm glad you came.
Sit down.
Diego found some documents in Cora's house
which contain proof of Emilia's anomalies
back when she was a mayor.
Well, Attorney? Have you read
and studied all of these?
Can these help our case?
Yes.
But no one should be able
to prove that we stole that.
Otherwise, the judge won't accommodate us.
Okay. We can't afford
to make any more mistakes.
I need a strong case against Emilia.
Well, then, we need a whistleblower.
A witness who can confirm her corruption.
I don't think we can depend
on Cora anymore.
We need someone else who can help us.
A name made a strong impression
while I was reviewing the documents.
Divine Uytengco.
Hold on.
I've heard that name before.
I know. Emilia buys her jewelry from her.
That's right. They're friends.
[Georgina] But the public doesn't know
about their connection.
-Divine!
-Oh, my gosh, Emilia.
-Look at you.
-Divine.
-You're so sexy.
-[Emilia chuckles]
-I missed you.
-I missed you too, Divine.
Long time no see.
The truth is, most of the
money Emilia embezzles
through the foundation
goes to Divine's bank account.
Really?
So, Attorney…
how many millions are we talking about?
Emilia has embezzled no
less than a hundred million
through her foundations.
And Divine…
knows the ins and outs
of her illegal transactions.
So, we need her on our side.
Divine Uytengco.
[Divine] Oh, by the way. How's Arnaldo?
He's all over the news.
My gosh, Divine.
Can we not talk about him?
You know, I don't want to be depressed.
And I came here for another reason.
Why? Are you going
to upgrade your jewelry?
[chuckles] No.
I need 20 million
transferred to my account.
That's a lot of money, darling.
I know. But that's my own money.
You're just safekeeping it for me.
Oh, yeah. [laughs]
I need it.
Hmm. I can sense that you're
funding an electoral campaign.
Darling, that devilish smile of yours?
I know that so well!
You're up to no good again.
[Emilia laughs]
Are you running against your
own father in this election?
[both chuckle]
[sighs]
That's a secret.
Stay tuned for the next episode.
Cheers to that, Divine!
-I know you so well.
-It's good to see you again.
[Ivy] Attorney, I want to
release this to the media.
If we release this to the media,
Divine Uytengco will be
dragged into this mess.
Then, I'll convince her
to become our witness against Emilia.
Okay, Ivy. We'll take care
of exposing this to the media.
[Ivy] We need to speed up the case.
But we need a refined plan,
or else everything will go
down once Arnaldo wakes up.
What happened to the investigation
into his shooting?
The Ardientes have a new suspect.
It's just a matter of time
before they get to them.
That's why I want you all to be careful.
Especially you two, Diego, Jepoy.
[tense music playing]
I need to find out who the
Ardientes' new suspect is.
[tense music playing]
Jepoy, Anna, I'll be off. Diego.
-Mom.
-Lily.
Mom, thank you for what you're doing,
and for all your help
organizing our plans.
Lily, don't thank me.
We're doing this for Poblacion Ardiente.
Yes.
You're just like your father.
He would've been so proud of you.
[instrumental theme music playing]
I miss him so much.
Whenever I remember Dad…
I can't help but feel sad.
It still hurts.
But seeing you…
makes me happy, Mom.
Especially now that I've
been given a second chance…
to be with you again.
Lily…
we'll never be apart again.
Thank you for finding me.
For not giving up.
Lily, I love you.
I love you too, Mom.
I love you so much, Mom.
[music continues]
[exhales] We really need to
speed up our plans,
so we can make up for lost time…
so all this can end,
and we can both be happy together.
Always be careful out there.
You too, Mom.
Attorney.
Take care of my mom.
Mom.
I'll see her out.
The doctor said…
you'll be discharged soon.
I know, Arnaldo.
I know…
you have so many things to tell me.
Because you saw with your own eyes…
who our real enemies are.
And I can't wait for you to wake up.
Rise and spit on the
graves of those people.
I will make sure
that our kingdom is still standing
when you wake up.
You are still my legacy.
And you will still have
a kingdom to inherit.
That is why…
I will go against Diego Torillo.
I will run for governor.
[reporter] Congressman Julio Ardiente
has shocked the public
by filing his candidacy for governor.
We're here now to interview
the congressman.
-Congressman.
-Yes?
[reporter on TV] Is Mayor Arnaldo
withdrawing his candidacy?
Is that why you're replacing him?
[Julio on TV] Are you
calling me a substitute?
Truth is…
I really don't like hearing the word
"withdraw."
In the Ardiente family,
I've never heard of
an Ardiente withdrawing from a fight.
It just so happens that
Mayor Arnaldo Ardiente-Torillo
is recuperating.
And of course, we can't turn our backs
on the people of Ardiente.
Somebody has to look after
the needs of each and every
one of our citizens.
Truth be told,
I could easily just retire
and enjoy the rest of my life.
But I'm doing this for our people.
To all the people of Ardiente,
who I've long considered
my children…
To all of you,
your Señor Julio is here once again,
asking for your help,
with the promise
that I will never abandon you.
They'll fight tooth and claw
to hold on to their power.
But I'll pry it from them.
Yes, they're powerful,
but more people believe in us.
No matter what happens,
we have to keep fighting.
-Fight for Diego!
Viva Ardiente.
Let's see how long your power
can protect you…
Julio Ardiente.
Papa?
You're replacing Arnaldo?
If not me, then who?
You? [chuckles]
Heaven forbid.
[Julio laughs]
[Ivy] From the very beginning, we knew the
Ardientes wouldn't let go of their power.
Diego, you need to get ready.
I can tell that this election's
going to be dirtier and bloodier.
Ivy, we're ready for
anything they throw at us.
Your announcement
was surprising, Congressman.
Even I didn't expect that.
Ivy, you should know by now
that I am full of surprises.
I also have a couple of aces up my sleeve.
Now, what I want to know
is if I can expect your
support, Miss Ivy Aguas.
Of course.
Of course, Congressman.
Whatever support I gave to Arnaldo,
I can double…
-or triple it for you.
-Wow…
My, my.
I'll forever be indebted
-to you, Miss Aguas.
-[Ivy chuckles]
Thank you.
Good morning, Emilia.
Oh, my.
It really did come true, didn't it?
My horoscope was so right today.
It said, "Emilia, you'll
be unlucky today."
All because I saw you!
Really?
I think your horoscope was inaccurate.
Haven't you been unlucky all your life?
[scoffs] What are you doing here?
You're not supposed to be here.
Didn't you get the memo?!
-Don't worry, Emilia.
-Can't you read?
I just came to pick up
the stuff I left behind.
-I won't stay long.
-[scoffs]
Well, that's a relief. I can rest easy.
You know what? You should disappear.
Evaporate. Forever!
Don't worry, I'll pray for you.
Thank you.
I appreciate that,
although I'm shocked that…
you actually pray.
Then again, you Ardientes
are good at putting up a front.
But then…
I think I've found my calling here.
Do you know what that calling is?
It's to make your life miserable.
Can I go now?
[Ivy] Oh, Jenny! Can you come with me?
[tense music playing]
[man] All right Diego. We got this.
-I'll leave it up to you.
-We've got this.
Nanny, we have lots of
supporters from the other town!
-Are those ready?
-Yes, almost.
-We still have a few here.
-Okay. Let's finish this.
-There we go.
-Good news.
Miss Cora is inside right now.
-She is?
-Let's go.
-Come on.
-Nanny.
-Go on. Sure.
-[indistinct chatter]
-My vote's for Diego.
[ominous music playing]
Miss, does Diego Torillo live here?
Yes. That's his place over there.
-Who was he asking about?
-Diego.
-Diego?
[woman] He was asking about
Diego. I wonder why…
[tense music playing]
Jenny, you can go now. I can manage here.
Diego.
Diego, we still have a good chance.
Miss Cora, thank you
very much for joining us.
This will be a big help.
I'm sorry for not cooperating before.
I was just afraid.
We're sorry for what we did too.
[motorcycle engine slowing down]
We're ready, Diego.
I've compiled all our evidence.
I've already spoken
to my contacts in the media.
They're waiting for us.
-[tricycle engine starts]
-[car horn honking]
[car horn honking]
[motorcycle engine starting]
What was that?
[car horn honking]
-Why are you blocking the way?
-I'm sorry, sir.
[man] My tricycle broke down.
[Jose] Don't you recognize
Congressman's car?
[man] Please tell him I'm sorry
for the inconvenience.
Never mind. Actually,
he asked us to help you.
[ominous music playing]
All right, boys. Help him.
Those Ardientes will never change,
no matter what tricks they pull.
Angels by day, demons at night.
'Cause that's what they really are.
[Diego] Those people will never change.
But what's important is that
the people want change.
Now, they know the truth
and are making a stand.
Look at that.
All for show.
[sighs]
[man] Why wouldn't it break down?
The road is full of potholes.
Because they're lining their
pockets with our tax money.
[woman] They're even pretending to help.
It's your fault!
You can't fool us anymore!
Auntie. Don't lose hope.
Our sacrifices will not be in vain.
[ominous music playing]
Diego and Jepoy?
How did they find out?
Auntie, excuse me.
-Sure.
-[phone ringing]
-[call disconnected]
-Diego.
Is that him?
It's him.
-[phone ringing]
-Hello, Jepoy.
Diego, are you on your way out?
I have good news.
Miss Cora agreed to
testify against Emilia.
She's with us right now.
-[line ringing]
-Jepoy… Jepoy, pick up.
All right. I'll catch up with you there.
Stop!
[Diego] Sure.
[Camia] Miss Cora…
thank you for changing your mind.
My conscience keeps eating at me.
Now I want to join you.
I'm ready to divulge Ma'am
Emilia's corrupt activities.
[line ringing]
[phone ringing]
Hold on. Excuse me.
-Mom.
-Hello.
Mom… Mom, are you with Jepoy and Diego?
Uh, just Diego. But we're on our way out…
to present the evidence against Emilia.
Mom… Mom, listen to me.
Tell Diego…
that his life is in danger.
Both him and Jepoy.
Julio has a shoot-to-kill
order against them.
Say goodbye, Diego Torillo.
[Ivy] Mom, Jepoy and Diego's lives
are in danger.
[ominous music playing]
[gunshots]
[crowd screaming]
-[bodyguard] Get down!
-[gunshots]
[crowd screaming]
-Get in!
-[crowd screaming]
-[gunshots]
-Hey! Come on! Move!
-[crowd screaming]
[shrieks]
-Nanny!
-Everyone, get inside!
[gunshots]
-[gunshots]
-[crowd screaming]
Mom! Mom, talk to me. Mom!
[gunshots]
[Georgina] Diego.
-Miss Camia is still outside.
-[gunshots]
[Jose] Congressman!
Police station?
Yes. We're here at
Mr. Diego Torillo's headquarters.
There's a shootout outside.
Send policemen here and an ambulance. Now.
-Let's go in! Come on! Come on!
-Diego!
Mom!
[grunts]
[groans]
[gunshots]
-[woman] Help me!
-[gunshots]
[gunshots]
-[muffled gunshot]
-Mom!
[Camia groans]
You're a monster, Julio Ardiente!
Camia Cruz!
Aunt Camia!
[Marlon] Diego!
Diego!
[Camia] Lily, dear…
Auntie?
[goon] Check if he's dead.
[grunts]
Auntie? Aunt Camia?
Auntie? Auntie?
[Jose] Let's go! Let's go!
Go!
Let's go!
Auntie? Auntie!
Help! Help! Batch!
-Camia! Camia!
-Help us!
-Come on! Let's go!
-Camia! Camia!
-Help!
-Camia!
-Miss Camia!
-Diego.
-The ambulance!
-Miss Camia!
-Help!
-Sir, hurry!
[Marlon] Open it! Get a stretcher!
-Go, Batch!
-Batch, what about our supporters?
Don't worry. I got them, Batch.
-Help them!
-We will, Batch. Now go!
-What about the other supporters?
-Where's Cora?
I got it. I got it. We'll help them.
-No!
-Hold on.
[mumbling]
[mumbles]
No. No, no, no. No, no, Mom.
You monsters…
Auntie. Auntie, you have to fight.
Auntie, don't leave us.
Auntie. Auntie.
[ambulance siren blaring]
[exhales]
[somber music playing]
-[grunting]
-[ragged breathing]
[exhales]
[indistinct chattering]
-Ivy. Ivy.
-Let go of me.
-Diego, let go.
-Ivy, wait.
The media are inside.
-The Ardientes will find out!
-Let go!
I don't care anymore!
Ivy. Ivy. Ivy.
-Diego!
-Ivy, stop it!
I want to see my mother!
Do you really want to see her?!
If you go in there,
you'll be putting your mother's
life in more danger!
All right! Go inside!
Ivy… Ivy, I know how you feel.
But right now, we have to think clearly.
Diego, I want to see my mother.
I want to see her right now.
Arnaldo, my son, finally you're home.
It's safer for him here at
home than at the hospital.
At least here, he'll be with us.
And I believe he can
recover faster if he's here.
You are so right, Papa.
I'm gonna take care of my son.
Come on, let's take him inside. Hurry.
[Emilia] Be careful, okay?
Careful now.
Let's go to our office.
[foreboding music playing]
[bodyguard] Move aside. Go on.
Let them through.
-Sir.
-Move aside! Let me through!
[woman] My son! Let me through! My son!
Doc, what happened to my son?
[woman] Doc! Doc!
[monitor beeping rhythmically]
[Ivy sobs]
Mom. Mom. Mom.
Mom, I'm sorry.
Mom.
Mom, I'm sorry. You got dragged into this.
[Ivy weeping]
[sentimental music playing]
Mom?
[monitor beeping rapidly]
[steady beep]
-Aunt Camia?
-Mom?
-Camia.
-Mom, no.
-Auntie!
-Mom! No!
-Mom!
-Doc!
-Mom! Mom!
Mom! Mom, no, no, no!
-Nurse.
-Mom, no!
-Excuse me, ma'am.
-Mom, come on. Mom!
Mom! Mom, don't leave me. Mom!
Check the vital signs.
Mom! Mom! No! No! No!
No!
Mom! Mom! No!
[nurse] Excuse me, ma'am.
You can't be here.
-Please revive my mom.
-I have to ask you to step out.
Revive my mom, Miss. Please!
Please help her!
[Ivy sobbing]
Our hitmen were able to ambush Madrigal.
But he got away.
What about Diego?
Diego is alive.
But many of his supporters got hurt.
And Camia Cruz?
There's no confirmation yet.
We're waiting to hear
if she's dead or alive.
Well…
make sure Diego knows…
he was the target of that ambush.
That way he'll know he's responsible
for what happened to his supporters.
Yes, sir.
Ma'am.
Papa? You issued an order to kill Diego?
Diego and Madrigal.
Because I suspect that those two
are the ones who shot Arnaldo.
But you know, Papa?
The little things
that you do for the family?
Makes me proud to be an Ardiente.
Viva Ardiente, Papa.
Viva Ardiente.
That was a really good one, Papa.
Bold move.
[Ivy] Make sure the whole
hospital is secured.
Don't worry. I'll take care of everything.
-Yes, ma'am.
-Thank you.
Who shot my mother?
[tense music playing]
Julio Ardiente.
[tense music continues]
[growls]
Julio, you bastard.
[suspenseful music swelling]
[Julio] Jaguar was the one
who tried to kill your son.
You betrayed me!
That's the gun I gave Madrigal.
He probably did that for personal reasons.
Then kill Madrigal!
We now know who did it.
I assume you feel guilty
for all the other people you've hurt.
They deserved every bullet
that flew all over that place!
[Ivy] So, it's Madrigal.
[Julio] And he is about to die.
He will definitely pay for this!
Come with me.
[theme music playing]